Mark Carr

5 Findon Road, Gosport, Hampshire, PO12 4EP 07738 637549 - markcarrrr@gmail.com

Introduction

I'm a Frontend Developer with over fifteen years experience. With my past UX experience I bring a great understanding of the needs of design and usability which I feel complement my frontend skills.

My core skills in pure CSS, HTML and JavaScript are matched well with my knowledge of CSS preprocessors, JavaScript libraries and frameworks along with task runners and packagers.

Case studies

Out of some of my recent work I am most proud of the dynamic <u>search results</u> I built. I used RequireJS and jQuery as necessary, JSDoc comments and Mocha for testing. There was some CSS I was particularly pleased with including the drilled down 'Narrow your results' <u>filter styling</u>.

My past work includes working on <u>ozy.com</u>. Though the site has been continually developed and refactored over the years the homepage still stays relatively true to my original build. The site was also featured as part of the A Responsive Web Design Podcast.

Recently I have gained valuable experience in using Bootstrap, implementing modals, progress bars, grid layouts, tooltips, forms and more.

I found a great <u>accessibility Grunt task</u> for a client project but it was missing one feature I needed. So in my spare time I added the feature and created a pull request. Other developers commented they would like the feature and the pull request was approved and merged in.

A personal highlight of mine was having a <u>codepen on picturefill</u> 'hearted' by <u>Chris Coyier</u>. I've followed Chris for many years and read many of his articles so it was a particularly proud moment for me.

I appreciate that looking at source code of live sites isn't always ideal and code changes over time. As such I have provided links to my <u>Github</u> and <u>Codepen</u> accounts.

Skills and knowledge

I have listed below the key skills I have as a quick reference:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- jQuery, RequireJS, Bootstrap
- SASS, LESS
- Git, Grunt, Yeoman, NPM, Bower
- Responsive mobile first development
- Cross browser/device knowledge
- Accessibility

Work history

I've worked to waterfall, Agile and Scrum practices and used JIRA on a day-to-day basis.

In addition to my working knowledge I feel I bring a calm and well thought manner. I easily get along with people and quickly feel part of a team wherever I have worked.

Gallagher Shilling - Frontend Developer (Contractor) - June 2016 to present

Styling and functionality for custom form elements. Building of login and account pages. Implementation of pension calculation pages.

John Wiley & Sons - UI Developer (Contractor) - September 2014 to May 2016

AJAX <u>search results</u>. Implementing multi site build process off of single dotCMS templates. AJAX <u>tabs</u> including 'more' link functionality. Analytical data tracking. Implementing the framework and tests for unit testing. Knowledge sharing through presentations at fortnightly online UI Developer meetings.

Abacus eMedia - Frontend Developer (Permanent) - May 2010 to August 2014

Core product development for in-house CMS. Bespoke custom site development. Responsive HTML emails. Accessibility techniques and considerations. Client handovers, training, demonstrations and online and person-to-person meetings.

B&Q - UI/UX Developer (Permanent) - June 2003 to May 2010

UI/UX ecommerce site development. Checkout path customer journeys and development. HTML email development. Promotional banners and targeted landing pages.

Bright Studios - Frontend Developer (Permanent) - *December 2000 to May 2003* Flash games and banners. Small business site development.

Education

BTEC NC in Computer Studies, Fareham College, September 2000 to April 2002.

Links

- Github https://github.com/markcarrrr
- Codepen https://codepen.io/markcarrrr/pens/popular/
- Twitter https://twitter.com/markcarrrr
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/markcarrrr

Personal

I live in the town of Gosport along the south coast of England with my wife Chrissie and our two young sons Jake and Harvey.

I'm a keen guitarist having studied for over twenty six years with a constant drive for betterment and gigging on and off over the years. Being dedicated and reliable has made me a valuable band member.

References

Excellent references available upon request.